Guide to the Cornwall Medical Miscellanea 1800-1946 MS 018 MS 018 MS 018
Cornwall Historical Society
Cornwall Medical Miscellanea
1800-1946
Cornwall Historical Society
Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
MS 018
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
This contains medical records relating to the town of Cornwall.
Provenance
Collected by local historian E.C. Starr.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
This contains medical records relating to the town of Cornwall. The collection includes general information about medical matters in the community, such as Ebenezer Jackson being quarantined in 1801 during a smallpox outbreak, but primarily consists of information about individual Cornwall doctors.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains general medical information regarding the town of Cornwall, CT and healthcare providers who worked there from 1800-1946.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically in the first series and alphabetically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading in the second series.
The files are grouped into 2 series:
Genreal Records
Individuals
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Cornwall (Conn.); Correspondence; Articles; obituaries; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
- General Records
  - List of Cornwall families approved for smallpox inoculation, 1800 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Emergency town order for quarantine, upon smallpox outbreak in North Cornwall, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agreement by Dr. A.M. Huxley to treat Cornwall paupers, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Individuals
  - Clippings on William W. Bierce, 1914; , undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter and biographical sketch sent to E.C. Starr from Dr. Edward M. Foote, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Election poster designed by Dr. Edward M. Foote, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Biography of Dr. Irving Louis Hamant, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Biography of Dr. E.B. Heady, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr from Dr. Joseph A.Livingston, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Joseph A. Livingston obituary, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter and biography of Dr. J.A. Livingston sent to E.C. Starr, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr regarding Dr. J.A. Livingston obituary, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hand-written copy of obituary of Dr. J.A. Livingston, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dr. J.A. Livingston signature, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photograph of Dr. J.A. Livingston, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr from Dr. W. Martin, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr from Dr. William H. Metcalf, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Burritt B. North account book, 1852-1861 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Obituaries for Dr. Joseph Howard North, 1919; , undated (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - William B. North obituary, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr about the sword of Dr. William B. North, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Genealogical information on Dr. George J. Northrop, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - E.C. Starr correspondence with Dr. Arthur M. Pratt, 1901; , undated (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Photograph of Dr. A.M. Pratt, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Receipt of Dr. Joseph Robinson for night call and consultation with Hubert Pratt, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Copy of receipts from Dr. Joseph Robinson and Dr. H.G. Stevens, 1907-1909 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Certification of vaccination by Dr. Joseph Robinson, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr from Dr. Francis S. Skiff, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Biography, with printed image, of Dr. F.S. Skiff, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr with information on Dr. Frederick T. Van Buren, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Receipts of Dr. W. Bradford Walker, 1923-1938 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Announcement of Dr. W. B. Walker’s nomination for Connecticut doctor of the year, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper image of Dr. W.B. Walker, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 36)